Claudio Silva, Java Developer

London, United Kingdom, 07308 475701, claudioc.cruzsilva@gmail.com

PROFILE

I have over 10 years of experience in software development, specializing in Java and related frameworks such as Spring MVC and Spring Boot. My focus is on providing architectural solutions that deliver optimal outcomes for clients, emphasizing best practices in software development, reusability, and code quality. For the past 6 years, I have been extensively involved with SAP Hybris Commerce (SAP CX) on both B2B and B2C projects. Throughout my career, I have transitioned from a developer to a technical leader and now serve as a technical leader/technical architect. In addition to managing technical requirements, I am passionate about coding and problem-solving.

I have led several integrations with systems including SAP ERP, Salesforce, and other external platforms using SCPI, DataHub, and Rest/SOAP/OData services. My technical skills include Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Apache Kafka, Tomcat, API development, Rest, SOAP, and MongoDB.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Apr 2023 — Present

Contract Java/Hybris Developer, Smart Europe

Remote

SAP Senior Developer consultant, working in international B2B Projects. Responsible for architecture solution, and implementation of new features for eCom. Customizing and provide new API (OCC). Working on integration scenario (Payment, SAP, Fleet, Shopping Cart, QuickOrder).

Technologies: Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Apache Kafka, AWS, OCC, SAP Commerce Cloud 2211, Spartacus Microsoft Azure, Kafka, SAP ECC, Rest, SOAP, Jenkins, Junit

Mar 2022 — Apr 2023

SAP Java Developer, Ammann Group,

Ettlingen

I'm working as a Senior Developer/Architect, responsible for the Ammann Portal/eShop. My main responsibility is working on development features, writing technical concepts, taking care of the backlog to coordinating the priority of the backlog that will be in the sprint. I'm also responsible for together with another enterprise architect, providing architecture solutions for the B2B scenarios, especially the integration between SAP Commerce with SAP ECC, SalesForce, and Microsoft Dynamics.

Technologies: Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Apache Kafka, AWS, OCC, SAP Commerce Cloud 2211, Spartacus Microsoft Azure, Kafka, SAP ECC, Rest, SOAP, Jenkins, Junit

Feb 2020 — Mar 2022

SAP Java/Hybris Developer, Sartorius GmbH

Göttingen

I'm working as a Senior Commerce Cloud Developer for Sartorius eShop, my main responsibilities are to provide improvement for the Sartorius B2B Shop, develop new features, and integrate between SAP Commerce, C4C, ECC, and Salesforce CRM. I'm also responsible for the Datahub customization, to optimize the integration process between Sartorius platforms with our **Technologies**: Java, Spring, Rest, SOAP, SAP ECC FUNCTION, Hybris 1811-2011, Hybris Backoffice, ERP, JavaScript, Bitbucket, Unit Test, Jenkins, Apache Solr.

Sep 2018 — Feb 2020

SAP Java/Commerce Senior Developer, Querplex GmbH

Nuremberg

Work Description: I'm working as a Senior Hybris Developer, providing architecture solutions for B2B and B2C scenarios, providing new features for our customers, and making demos for the pre-sales area. Using standard SAP Hybris accelerators to optimize the development process, customize datahub for custom integration, configuration transaction on SAP ERP. Projects:

- Deprag I was part of the team responsible for delivering the first release of myDeprag eCommerce, a B2B
 Eshop for Deprag customers. I was responsible for setup initial data, configuring and customizing datahub
 integration, implementing hotfolder process to load media, and creating the media container for products.
 I also customize the registration process, product page, product detail, product list page, synchronous
 price, SOLR, and RFC call using JCO.
- Covetrus B2B Responsible to migrate the old hybris implementation to the new release 2105, using spartacus as frontend and sap commerce cloud OCC to provide the APIs. I was part of the team responsible to customize the APIS and Components for Product, Login, My Account, Checkout, Help Panel, and Page Components.
- JOWAT B2B I was responsible to customize datahub extensions to optimize the integration between the B2B eShop and ERP. I had the chance to configure SCPI connection for the first integrations.

I'm working as a Senior Hybris Developer, providing architecture solutions for B2B and B2C scenarios, providing new features for our customers, and making POC for the pre-sales area. Using standard SAP Hybris accelerators to optimize the development process, customize datahub for custom integration, configuration transaction on SAP ERP. Projects:

- Carrefour Brazil Carrefour is an international hypermarket chain founded in France in 1960. In 2004.
 I was responsible to maintain and developing new features for the OMS, creating and defining new business processes to add business logic during the checkout process and after placing the order. Providing integration with SAP ERP by datahub, and synchronizing the data to keep the status of the order updated. I was also supporting the external consulting to provide development on the checkout process, product page, product detail page, and developing RFC call to integrate price on PDP.
- Editora Abril Brazilian publisher headquartered in the city of Sao Paulo. I was responsible for setting up the hybris commerce, configuring datahub, and customizing to load the master data from the ERP. I was also part of the team responsible to discuss and define architecture solutions for the project. One of the main Hybris modules that I have to customize on this project was checkout, product detail page, product catalogs, product listing page, payment integration, base store configuration.
- Lepostiche Is the largest chain of bags, luggage, and travel accessories in Brazil. I was part of the team responsible for the migration of the eCommerce from Magento to Hybris Commerce. My main responsibility was to set up the initial data for the project, configure the WCMS site, base store, and catalogs. I was also responsible for setting up a data hub to integrate customer and product (DEBMAS and MATMAS) and developing JCO to communicate via RFC with SAP ERP as well. Working directly to customize the payment types, checkout, order management, product detail page, product list page, listing price, categories, and product catalogs. Technologies: Java, Spring MVC, Spring Integration, Datahub, RFC, ERP, Rest, SOAP, JSP, JSTL, TAG, HQSL, H4NA, SQL Server, Hybris release 5.7 to 6.7

May 2015 — Apr 2016

Senior Software Engineer, Verx Consulting

São Paulo

I have worked as a Senior Java Software Engineer for multiple projects to provide the best solutions for Verx's customers. I was responsible to develop new features, providing architecture solutions, and also as a technical lead. I've been in multiple customers working as a full-stack developer, using the most innovative frameworks for backend and frontend. Projects:

- UOL Brazilian news, product, payment, and internet service that belongs to Grupo Folha, with over 114
 million views per month. I was responsible for maintaining the CMS and developing new landing pages
 for the website.
- Drogasil One of the biggest pharma companies in Brazil, with revenue over 1 Billion USD yearly. I was
 responsible to support and developing the distribution center systems, providing new implementation,
 and developing APIs to enable the communication between the warehouse system and courier system.
 Technologies: Java, Spring MVC, Rest, SOAP, Angular, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MongoDB, MySQL,
 Oracle, Maven, Git.

Jan 2013 — May 2015

Full-stack Software Engineer, CDI Consulting

Belem

Job title: Full-stack Software Engineer Jan 2013 - Mai 2015 Work Description: I worked as a Full Stack Developer, to develop new features for the ADMLog system (Logistics System of the Bank of the Para State) using Java technology, RMI, Hibernate, JPA, JSF. Maintenance of scripts in the database, SQLServer, configuration, and installation of WebContainer Apache TomCat. Tests performance, and deployment. I was responsible for the development of new projects, using PMI management practices, elaborating requirements traceability, scope document, and use case diagram. Technologies: Java, Spring, JSF, JSP, ApacheTomcat, Angular, NodeJs, Hibernate, PLSQL. Technologies: Java, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, JSP, MySQL Maven.

Jan 2012 — Dec 2012

Software Engineer, DWB Databases - Bradesco Bank

São Paulo

Job title: Software Engineer Jan 2012 - Dez 2012 Work Description: I worked with the development and maintenance of Bradesco (Internet Banking) systems, in the investments of individual and corporate clients. Netapresas (Private area for Bradesco client companies) and Home Broker (Electronic Trading, buying, and selling of actions). Using Object-Oriented development methodology - UML, J2EE platform, data persistence with JPA and Hibernate, reports with JasperReport, AWB (View layer with JSF components), data modeling tool (ERWIN 3.5.2), Documentation (Office, MS Project, MS Visio), HTML programming language v.4.0, JavaScript, Java. IDE development (Eclipse) application servers: Tomcat, WebSphere, and Jboss. Page4 Follow-up of delivery of sources to the technology sector of Bradesco, monitoring of tests, elaborating PV. I had continuous participation in system homologation, along with Bradesco's managers, preparation of checklist, the configuration of homologation environment, also acting with Analysis, mapping, and functional specifications for the Investment Website of Banco Bradesco (ShopInvest). Project Management using PMBook metrics. Utilization of Banco Bradesco's methodology, performing metrics through APF and physical metrics of projects received a survey of requirements with the business manager, analysis of the demands generated for the Stock Room. Elaboration of the proposal with outsourced companies and validation of technical solutions presented.

Source control and application compilation as well as deployment rollout in production. Technologies: Java, J2EE, Hibernate, JPA, JSF, ApacheCXF, Java Server Pages, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL Server, Maven, Gradle, Git

Jan 2011 — Dec 2011

Junior Software Engineer

Belem

Work Description: Maintenance and development of new features for one of the most important systems that support the logistics of resources between the state and the county. Providing development of new REST and SOAP APIs to enable external systems consuming mandatory data that it's mandatory for another business logic that belongs to the finance department, including payroll and HR. I was also responsible for directly communicating with users to understand the requirements and support the business team to create users' stories. Technologies: Java, Hibernate, JPA, JasperReport, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Angular, MySQL, Oracle, Maven, Git

MFG/Pro (ERP)

Eclipse (Software)

EDUCATION

Software Development and Information Technology, Faculdade Ideal Devry

SKILLS Java

Business To Business Simple Object Access Protocol

Writing (SOAP)

Amazon Web Services Coordinating

Junit Project Management Institute

(PMI) Methodology

Hypermarket Investments
Management Jenkins

Acting Apache Tomcat SAP ERP

Mapping Persistence
Zope (CMS) Spring Boot
Bitbucket Hibernate (Java)

Erwin (Data Modeling Software)
Gradle

Hybris Source (Game Engine)

Traceability Data Modeling

Java (Programming Language)

Java Platform Enterprise Edition

Requirements Traceability (J2EE)

Angular (Web Framework) JavaScript (Programming

Server Pages

Apache Kafka

Language)

Integration

SAP CRM Project Management

Sales

Consulting

Registration

HyperText Markup Language
(HTML)

Microsoft Azure
Salesforce.Com

FourGen Computer-Aided Business Logic

Software Engineering (CASE)
Tools
Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Application Programming
Interface (API)

Progress OpenEdge (IDE)
Agile Software Development

Magento MySQL

SQL (Programming Language) Web Content Management

Communications System (WCMS)

Electronic Trading

Scrum (Software Development)

Data Hub

MongoDB Classification And Regression Tree (CART)

LANGUAGES English Portuguese Native speaker